Guide to the League for Industrial Democracy Records TAM.049
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
League for Industrial Democracy Records
1920-1996
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
League for Industrial Democracy
TAM.049
46.25 Linear Feet in 40 manuscript boxes, 25 record cartons, 1 half manuscript box, and 1 oversize flat box.
The League for Industrial Democracy (LID) was founded in 1905 as the Intercollegiate Socialist Society by democratic socialist intellectuals to bring "education for the new social order" to the nation's campuses, but its name was changed in 1920 to broaden appeal and better reflect aims of social ownership and democratic control of industry. This collection contains the LID's records from the 1920s-1990s, including financial and membership records, correspondence, meeting minutes, conference and lecture materials, and other materials related to the activities and operation of the League for Industrial Democracy.
Historical/Biographical Note
The League for Industrial Democracy (LID) was founded in 1905 as the Intercollegiate Socialist Society by democratic socialist intellectuals to bring "education for the new social order" to the nation's campuses, but its name was changed in 1920 to broaden appeal and better reflect aims of social ownership and democratic control of industry. In 1922, Norman Thomas (1884-1968; later the Socialist Party's head and presidential candidate) joined Harry W. Laidler as Co-Director. LID campaigned throughout 1920s and 1930s for public power development through the Committee on Coal and Giant Power, a spin off group established in conjunction with American Civil Liberties Union and chaired by H. S. Rauschenbush. The LID also sought to preserve civil liberties through the Emergency Committee for Strikers Relief (chaired by John Herling) which aided strikers across the nation with direct relief, organization, and the formation of defense committees for persecutred activists. Laidler's retirement as Director in 1957 led to the succession of Sidney Hertzberg, who aimed to make LID a forum for liberal study. Later leader, Michael Harrington (1928-1989), sought to build constituency of labor, intellectuals, and Black civil rights activists. By the later 1970s, the LID had become politically associated with Social Democrats USA (a grouping of union officials and others with roots in the socialist and Trotskyist movements, whose posture is militantly anti-communist but also retains a commitment to aspects of liberalism), and although still extant as of 2010, it appears to be inactive.
The LID led the defense of Athos Terzani, Italian antifascist framed (in 1933) for murder by (pro-fascist group) Khaki Shirt leader Art Smith, which resulted in Smith's own indictment for perjury. During the Great Depression the LID sought to alleviate plight of unemployed by campaigning for national unemployment insurance, organizing unions of the unemployed by campaigning for national unemployment insurance, opening "recreation huts" (which resembled settlement houses), and publishing The Unemployed, a magazine to bring the socialist vision to the jobless. During Socialist Party schisms of 1930s, Norman Thomas used his LID position to secure leadership of the Militant faction to battle Old Guard. During World War II, the LID supported nation's war effort while defending the social advances of 1930s. Its post-war posture was anti communist.
Separated Materials
In 1987, sound recordings were separated from the collection to OH 500.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records may have been initially donated by the League for Industrial Democracy in the early 1970s. Additional accessions were donated by the League for Industrial Democracy in 1993 and 2001. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 2001.192, 2001.193, and NPA 2008.016
Scope and Contents
The League for Industrial Democracy Records (dated 1920-1996) contain minutes, correspondence, photographs, pamphlets, financial documents, and membership records created by the League for Industrial Democracy (LID). The first portion of this collection is fully processed, and consists of meeting minutes of the Board of Directors, 1920-1970; committee correspondence, including the Committee on Coal and Giant Power and the Emergency Committee for Strikers Relief; membership lists; schedules for lecture tours; information relating to the work of the Chicago Workers' Committee for the Unemployed Chairman Karl Borders; transcripts of annual conferences; press clippings; material on the defense of Athos Terzane; a scrapbook of photos from southern labor Chautauquas; funding requests; and a collection of labor songs.
The second portion of collection is partially processed and includes box-level descriptions. These materials contain administrative and financial records from the 1960s to the 1990s, which include articles, pamphlets, fundraising records, correspondence, research files, Board of Directors and Executive Committee minutes, and membership files. There is a significant amount of material documenting LID's annual conferences and institutes, including material related to their United States-wide Student-Labor Institutes.
Additionally, the collection contains black-and-white photographs of individuals and events between the 1950s and 1970s. Included among these materials are negatives and photographs from a disassembled scrapbook.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series. Files in Series I: Processed Records arranged alphabetically by topic. Series II: Addendum has not been arranged by an archivist. Series III: Photographs is arranged alphabetically by name of featured individual and by subject. The series arrangement of the records is as follows:
Series I: Processed Records
Series II: Addendum
Series III: Photographs
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
League for Industrial Democracy Printed Ephemera Collection (PE 033)
League for Industrial Democracy by-laws, clippings, and publications can be found on microfilm reel R-7914.
Harry Laidler Papers (TAM 047)
Harry Laidler Photographs (PHOTOS 009)
Minutes (administrative records); Clippings (information artifacts); Photographic prints.; Songs (document genre); Unemployed; Labor -- United States.; Right and left (Political science).; Power resources -- United States.; Unemployed -- United States.; Socialism -- United States.; League for Industrial Democracy; Rustin, Bayard, 1912-1987; Borders, Karl, 1891-; Herling, John; Harrington, Michael, 1928-1989; Laidler, Harry W. (Harry Wellington), 1884-1970; Hertzberg, Sidney; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968; Rauschenbach, H. S.; Terzani, Athos; Emergency Committee for Strikers Relief; Committee on Coal and Giant Power
- Series I: Processed Records, 1921-1970
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Content Note
  This series contains the records of the League for Industrial Democracy from the 1920s-1970s. This include correspondence with individuals, chapters, and other organizations; board of directors and other meeting minutes; financial records; annual conferences; membership files; materials from their lecture series; pamphlets; publications; materials generated by Harry Laidler; and other subject files.
  - About LID, 1925-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Activities, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Activities, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Activities, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Activities, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Activities, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Activities, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Activities, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Activities, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Activities, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Activities, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Activities, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Activities, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Activities, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Activities, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Activities, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Activities, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Activities, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Activities, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Activities, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Activities, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Activities, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Activities, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Activities, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Activities, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Activities, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Activities, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Activities (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Advertising, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Advertising, 1956-1961 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Amalgamated Bank, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - American Appeal, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Articles, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Articles, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Articles, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Articles, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Articles, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Articles, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Articles (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Attacks on LID by Conservative Groups, 1920-1929 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Attacks on LID by Conservative Groups (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Benedict, John K., 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Benedict, John K., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Benedict, John K., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Benedict, John K., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bequests, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Biographical Material (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Blanshard, Paul, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Blanshard, Paul, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Board of Directors, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Board of Directors, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Board of Directors, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Board of Directors, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Board of Directors, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Board of Directors, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Board of Directors, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Board of Directors, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Board of Directors, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Board of Directors, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Brockton, 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Chapters (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Chapters, NY, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chapters, NY, 1942-1945 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chapters, NY, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chapters, NY, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Chapters, NY, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Chapters, NY, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Chapters, NY, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Chapters, NY, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Chapters, NY, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Chapters, NY, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Chapters, NY, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Chapters, NY, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Chapters, NY, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Chapters, NY, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Chapters, NY, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Chapters, NY, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chapters, NY, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Chapters, NY, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Chapters, NY, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Chapters, NY (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Chapters, Other Cities, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chapters, Other Cities, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Chapters, Other Cities, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Chapters, Other Cities, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Chapters, Other Cities, 1956-1961 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Chapters, Other Cities (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Clippings (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Committee, Administrative, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Committee, Administrative (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Committee on Coal and Giant Power, 1924-1926 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Committee on Coal and Giant Power, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Committee on Coal and Giant Power, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Committee on Coal and Giant Power - Finances, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Committee on Coal and Giant Power - Finances, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Economic Policy (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Committee, Fifty-Second Annual Conference, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Committee, Finance, 1927-1928 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Committee, Finance, 1950-1955 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Committee, Finance, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Committee, Finance, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Committee, Finance, 1958-1961 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Committee, International Affairs/Relations, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Committee, Labor Advisory, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Committee, Natural Resources, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Committee, Nominations (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Committee, Pamphlet, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Committee, Pamphlet, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Committee, Pamphlet, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Committee, Pamphlet, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Committee, Pamphlet, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Committee, Pamphlet, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Committee, Pamphlet, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Committee, Pamphlet, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Committee, Pamphlet, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Committee, Publications (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Committee, Reorientation, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Committee, Reorientation, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Committee, Research (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Committee to Study Constitution & Bylaws, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Conference, Annual (20th), 1925 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Conference, Annual (30th), 1935 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Conference, Annual (32nd), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Conference, Annual (35th), 1940 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Conference, Annual (40th), 1945 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Conference, Annual (41st), 1946 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Conference, Annual (42nd), 1947 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Conference, Annual (43rd), 1948 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Conference, Annual (44th), 1949 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Conference, Annual (44th), 1949 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Conference, Annual (45th), 1950 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Conference, Annual (45th), 1950 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Conference, Annual (45th), 1950 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Conference, Annual (45th), 1950 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Conference, Annual (46th), 1951 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Conference, Annual (46th), 1951 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Conference, Annual (46th) - Press Releases and News Clippings, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Conference, Annual (46th) - Speakers, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Conference, Annual (47th), 1952 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Conference, Annual (48th), 1953 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Conference, Annual (49th), 1954 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Conference, Annual (50th), 1955 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Conference, Annual (50th), 1955 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Conference, Annual (50th) - Clippings and Press Releases, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Conference, Annual (50th) - Form Letters and Notices, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Conference, Annual (50th) - Speakers, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Conference, Annual (51st), 1956 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Conference, Annual (51st) - Form Letters and Notices, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Conference, Annual (51st) - Speakers, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Conference, Annual (52nd), 1957 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Conference, Annual (52nd) - Form Letters and Notices, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Conference, Annual (52nd) - Speakers, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Conference, Annual (53rd), 1958 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Conference, Annual (54th), 1959 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Conference, Annual (54th), 1959 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Conference, Annual (54th) - Journal, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Conference, Annual (55th), 1960 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Conference, Annual (55th) - Journal, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Conference, Annual (55th) - Speakers, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Conference, Annual (56th), 1961 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Conference, Annual (56th) - Journal, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Conference, Annual (56th) - Speakers, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Conference, Annual (57th), 1962 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Conference, Annual (58th), 1963 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Conference, Annual (60th), 1965 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Conference, Annual (61st), 1966 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Conference, Annual (62nd), 1967 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Conference, Annual (64th), 1969 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Conference, Annual (65th), 1970 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Conference, Delinquency, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Conference, June, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Conference, June (23rd), 1937 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Conference, June (24th), 1938 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Conference, June (25th), 1939 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Conference, June (26th), 1940 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Conference, June (27th), 1941 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, Regional, 1928-1929 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Conference, Summer (17th) - Proceedings, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Conference, Summer (18th), 1932 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Conference, Summer (19th), 1933 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Conference, Summer (20th), 1934 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Conference, Summer (21st), 1935 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Conference, Summer (22nd), 1936 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Conference, Winter, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Conference, Winter - Dinner, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Conference, Winter, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Conferences, Various (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Contacts (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence A-D, 1927-1928 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence E-H, 1927-1928 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence I-M, 1927-1928 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence N-R, 1927-1928 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence S-V, 1927-1928 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence W-Z, 1927-1928 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1928 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1928 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Administration, 1956-1961 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Books and Manuscripts, 1957-1961 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Foreign, 1927-1928 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Form Letters - Board and Committee Meetings, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Inquiries, 1927-1928 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Letters of Introduction and Reccomendation, 1950-1951 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Letters of Introduction, 1927-1928 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Literature, 1950-1951 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Literature, 1957-1958 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Literature, 1959-1961 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Post Office, 1928 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Post Office, 1950-1951 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Post Office, 1957-1960 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Power, 1927-1928 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Requests, 1927-1928 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Delegates, 1950-1951 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Delegates, 1957-1961 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Dinner for Abrams, Charles, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Dinner for Clapp, Gordon and Walter Frank, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Dinner for Coldwell, M.J., 1944 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Dinner for Counts, George and Abraham Lefkowitz, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Dinner for Dewey, John (90th Birthday), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Dinner for Dewey, John (90th Birthday), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Dinner for Dewey, John (90th Birthday), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Dinner for Humphrey, Hubert, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Dinner for Kilpatrick, William (85th Birthday), 1956 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Dinner for Kilpatrick, William (90th Birthday), 1961 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Dinner for Russell, Bertrand, 1927 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Dinner for Thomas, Norman, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Dinner for Thomas, Norman (75th Birthday), 1959 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Dissent Magazine (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - Briggs Strike, Detroit, 1932-1933 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - Continental Congress of Workers & Farmers, 1932-1933 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - Doll & Toy Workers Strike, New York, 1932-1933 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - Dressmakers Strike, New York, 1932-1933 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1932-1933 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - General Defense Committee, Chicago, 1932-1933 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - John Herling - Personal Correspondence, 1932-1933 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - Kentucky Miners, 1932-1933 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - Marine Workers' Defense Committee, 1932-1933 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - Massachusetts Shoe & Leather Workers, 1932-1933 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - Miscellaneous, 1932-1933 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - Mooney and Scotsboro Defense, 1932-1933 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - North Carolina, 1932-1933 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - Pennsylvania Miners, 1932-1933 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - Progressive Miners of America, 1932-1933 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief - West Virginia Miners, 1932-1933 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Employment, 1927-1928 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Events (non-LID) (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Executive Director Search, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 9)